<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ethansager.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ethansager.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-12-28T02:03:14+00:00</updated><id>https://ethansager.github.io/feed.xml</id><subtitle>My site </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A blog about blogs I like</title><link href="https://ethansager.github.io/blog/2025/blogs-I-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A blog about blogs I like"/><published>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ethansager.github.io/blog/2025/blogs-I-like</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ethansager.github.io/blog/2025/blogs-I-like/"><![CDATA[<p>I read a couple blogs. Here are some of my favorites organized by topic.</p> <h2 id="data-blogs">Data Blogs</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://blog.djnavarro.net/">Notes from a data witch</a>: Navarro writes about statistics, R, and data science with interesting tech tid bits.</li> <li><a href="https://datacolada.org/">Data Colada</a>: Mostly follow to keep up with interesting deep dives into replication drama.</li> <li><a href="https://www.argmin.net/">arg min</a>: Ben Recht has a great set of posts from his class on machine learning it also goes along with his book Patterns, Predictions, and Actions.</li> <li><a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/">statmodeling</a>: Andrew Gelman is a prolific blogger in statistics and data science. I mostly follow to keep up with his thoughts on Bayesian statistics.</li> </ul> <h2 id="development-economics">Development Economics</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://developmentekko.substack.com/">Development Ekko</a>: Julie Zollmann is a wonderful person and an excellent writer who mostly focuses on topics you don’t see talked about much such as the frequency of mobile money usage.</li> <li><a href="https://www.global-developments.org/">Global Developments</a>: Oliver Kim writes mostly about historical development economics and does a great job of connecting disparate topics.</li> <li><a href="https://voxdev.org/blogs">VoxDev</a>: Alot of the blogs are written by Oliver Hanney who I really enjoy reading but they also have guest bloggers.</li> <li><a href="https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/impactevaluations">Development Impact</a>: One of the few blogs that covers really specific design and measurement issues in depth. I get excited anytime David McKenzie writes a post.</li> </ul> <h2 id="politics-of-development">Politics of Development</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.africanistperspective.com/">An Africanist Perspective</a>: Ken Opalo who also happens to be a professor at Georgetown writes about both macro and micro issues with a interesting lense pushing back on the simple narratives that are often presented.</li> <li><a href="https://katieauth.substack.com/">Aid Interrupted</a>: Katie Auth writes about the poltics of foreign aid with a focus on the US.</li> <li><a href="https://toddmoss.substack.com/">Eat More Electrons</a>: Todd Moss who also has a great book on the politics of development in Africa writes about the how eletricity access and energy policy is inherently political.</li> </ul> <h2 id="public-intelectuals-cosmopolitan-polymaths-or-just-some-people-who-write-on-a-variety-of-topics">“Public Intelectuals” “Cosmopolitan polymaths” or just some people who write on a variety of topics</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.noahpinion.blog/">Noahpinion</a>: I have a love hate relationship with this blog at times me and Noah Smith are really on the same wavelength both topically and argumentively other times it feels like he just had to write a post which of course I get given his profession.</li> <li><a href="https://worksinprogress.co/">Works in Progress</a>: Though technically a magazine this is a great collection of long form essays on a variety of topics I loved Brian Albrecht’s piece on using the Olley-Pakes decomposition to better understand monopolies.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="misc"/><category term="data-science"/><category term="economics"/><category term="politics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[mostly data science but some economics and politics as well]]></summary></entry></feed>